Andre Hulet RESUME

806 NE Failing Street, Portland OR 97212 | andrehulet@gmail.com | 503.468.8606

Summary

Business Systems Manager: Highly capable as a manager leading teams to deliver complex projects and programs. Extensive experience analyzing and optimizing business models and processes, especially to create software applications and enterprise system integrations. Clients have included Fortune 500 companies and major governmental organizations. Specialties include Level-of-Effort estimation and planning, team leadership, business modeling, the integration of business systems with software applications, software development methodology, enterprise architecture, technology selection and design.

Professional Experience

Consultant, Well Made Systems, LLC. Nov 2012-present. Currently providing business analysis and project management services as an independent consultant.

Lead consultant on Business Process Improvement project for the Technologies division of Denver International Airport.
Performing analysis of unit that delivers telecom, internet and TV services to businesses operating at DIA; leading process
improvement workshop; developing initiatives to improve business process execution and software implementations; writing
policies and procedures to support improved processes and systems using the ITIL framework and Information Mapping
techniques.

Delivery Director, Spatial Development International. Feb-Nov 2012. Developed portfolio management process and tools for this GIS consulting firm. Also led large projects using state-of-the-art delivery methodologies.

- Oversaw 58% increase of monthly revenue and 20% increase in revenue per employee.
- For Sound Transit, Re-structured team and re-chartered client stakeholders to deliver software solution in 2.5 months, originally scheduled for 5 months.
- Was lead consultant for ETO's Enterprise GIS development project. Led integration planning, technology selection and prototyping an ESRI enterprise GIS system integrated with ETO's business intelligence warehouse, running on SAP Business Objects.

Director of Business Systems, Clean Energy Works Oregon. Oct 2010 to Feb 2012. Was responsible for all aspects of business systems, including program software applications, reporting, and core IT functions.

- Defined and developed business process and system definitions for 20MM energy efficiency program in OR. Led the creation
 of user roles, business rules, and validations for 18 processes within the program workflow. Software derived and built on the
 Django framework from process definitions currently serving hundreds of business users and thousands of public customers.
- Led multi-organization and multi-discipline team through review of process definitions and creation of enterprise software business requirements. Document was basis for procurement of 3-year systems support contract issued by CEWO and sister program Community Power Works.

Senior IS Manager, Critigen, LLC. Sept 2009 to Sept 2010.

- Led a blended team that analyzed GeoEye's process and orchestration requirements for its Consolidated Imagery Catalogue System. Created process orchestration design that included enterprise workflow from satellite downlink to sale of imagery. Was implemented with MS BizTalk.
- Was the project manager for technical services to the City of San Jose's Solar America Cities program. Led the effort to
 develop financial calculation tools for solar power installations in the City. The tools were integrated with existing GIS tools
 for site selection of over 200 locations using the SAFE methodology for determining photo-voltaic potential from high
 resolution imagery.
- Served as client services manager for the Energy Sector in North America. Developed business relationships, created market collateral and led demonstrations of technical solutions for energy clients.

Senior IS Manager, CH2M HILL, Inc. Aug 2004 to Sept 2009.

- Led a blended team that developed the end user applications for GeoEye's GeoFUSE Online Maps
 (http://geofuse.geoeye.com/maps/Map.aspx). Introduced Agile delivery techniques to client. Implemented true SOA to allow searching on the web, in Google Earth and in ArcGIS desktop. Delivered products to production under budget and in one-quarter timeframe.
- Lead analyst and PM for effort to map the business processes and create the solution architecture for the BAAQMD Grants
 Online Application Tool. Solution created a secure, online process for Bay Area companies to apply for air quality
 improvement funds.
- Was the principal project manager for Plum Creek's Central Title System development. System controlled title documents
 and geography for nation-wide land holdings. Oversaw and facilitated work of multiple distributed internal and external
 teams, including those under separate contract. The GIS application integrated Windows forms, ArcSDE and SharePoint via
 web services. Application scaled enterprise-wide using Citrix in period pre-dating appropriate web editing technology.

- Managed a development team to create Version 2.0 of CARROT the California Climate Action Registry's online greenhouse
 gas reporting software. Organizations can record, manage and certify reporting of Greenhouse Gas emissions. System
 conformed to multiple environmental protocols and was built according to application architecture best practices for
 scalability and extensibility.
- Worked with T-Mobile's RF Engineering group to map data flow and data management processes for cell tower inventory control. Also led technology review and prototype development for replacement of T-Mobile's Nationwide Coverage Check application.
- Served as Software Development Practice manager for EMS's Western Region. Supervised staff career development, was responsible for maintaining staff project utilization, provided quality assurance and oversaw the use of good development practices. Helped lead the development of the nation-wide community of practice.
- Served as EMS Principal for for software testing and quality assurance. Was part of a national team to establish a comprehensive solution development lifecycle methodology for EMS Division. Created good practice guidelines, templates, test case and unit test examples. Developed coursework for EMS career development center.

Business Systems Analyst/Developer, Gillette, Inc. Feb 2001 to Aug 2004.

- Received training in Lean Manufacturing, "Blitz Kaizan" and value stream mapping process improvement methodologies. Was
 lead analyst and software developer for numerous internal initiatives to upgrade the manufacturing process for Gillette's
 North American Oral Care division. Over a 3 year span, NA plant changed from least effective operation in Gillette to the
 benchmark in 3 out of 5 top-level corporate KPIs.
- Was lead analyst and developer for the re-write of the Professional Products Group system integration. Was on team that
 redesigned entire manufacturing and distribution process. Was lead designer for integrations between resource planning,
 manufacturing PLC, warehouse, inventory and shipping systems. Project received 3rd place in Gillette's world-wide
 Innovation Challenge in 2004.

College Instructor, University of California, Irvine. Sept 1998 to Dec 2000.

• Taught rhetoric & composition and creative writing to undergraduates. Was twice selected for departmental distinction in teaching.

Senior Staff Scientist, Woodward-Clyde, June 1994 to Aug 1998.

• Designed and developed software applications for this environmental engineering firm.

Research Assistant, Group Health Cooperative. Feb 1991 - May 1994.

 Performed research tasks, stastical analysis, created trial and survey designs in population science for the Centers for Health Studies and Promotion.

Technology Experience

MS Windows, Linux (SuSE, RedHat, Ubuntu), .NET, Django, ESRI ArcGIS, Google Earth Enterprise, MS BizTalk, SharePoint, Drupal. Python, C-type languages, VB languages, JavaScript. Services (web and RPC). Admin and programming of MS SQL and PostGRESQL, admin of Oracle. Source control with SubVersion & TFS, modeling with Sparx EA & Visio. Legacy tech, e.g. AS\400, RPG, Paradox, Foxpro, Avenue.

Education & Registrations

- M.F.A., English, University of California, Irvine, California (2000)
- B.A., Sociology and Anthropology, Carleton College, Northfield, Minnesota (1990)
- Project Management Institute, Portland Chapter

Professional References

- Rob McGarty | Director, Client Solutions | EnergySavvy, Seattle, WA | 206-295-7760 | rob@energysavvy.com
- **Diane Ferington** | Section Manager, Existing Homes | The Energy Trust of Oregon, Portland, OR | 503-544-6589 | diane.ferington@energytrust.org
- Greg Quirk | Cloud Delivery Executive | Microsoft Corporation | 303-888-5045 | gregquirk@comcast.net